Female Speaker 1: Modern crime novels are very different from the stories of the past.
These days, the main characters aren’t only private investigators – they’re also FBI agents or journalists.
In some stories, there’s a group of people trying to catch a criminal,
and in other stories, the detectives are either older or younger than usual.
Male Speaker 1: Going to live in a new place can be very exciting,
but it’s also a lot of work.
The first thing to do is pack all your things into boxes.
Write on each box which room it’s for and what’s inside.
Put the furniture in your new place before you take the boxes – that makes it easier to find your things.
Female Speaker 1: Some people prefer modern architecture,
but buildings from the past can be good for a city.
Old houses and palaces are interesting because they tell us about how people once lived and worked.
Some are also very beautiful, so visitors come to the city to see them.
Male Speaker 2: The job of a police detective is very different from what we see on TV.
In real life, detectives work on many different crimes, not only murders.
In the UK, some detectives start as police officers
and then do an exam when they have enough experience.
Others train for the job when they finish university.
Male Speaker 3: Most of us feel safe in our houses because we spend a lot of time there.
But many people go to hospital each year because of something that happened at home.
There are dangers in all of the rooms, but one big problem is people falling over furniture in the living room.